Guide to the Tracy Family Corporate Towing Minute Books AIA.021
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tracy Family Corporate Towing Minute Books
1917-1983
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tracy Towing Corporation (N.Y.)
AIA.021
4.5 Linear Feet in 4 record cartons and 1 manuscript box
The collection comprises minute books of the various Tracy family tugboat companies operating in New York harbor between 1917 and 1983. Three brothers, John, Michael J. and Thomas Tracy, organized the Tracy Towing Line in 1917. The Tracy family sisters Catherine and Helen also sat on the board of the various companies the family created for their tugboat and towing business. The company was located at 1 Broadway in New York City with additional offices in Brooklyn.
Scope and Contents
The collection comprises minute books of the various Tracy family tugboat companies operating in New York harbor between 1917 and 1983.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Marilyn Tracy, Anne Bricker, and Irene van Houten, 2002. The accession number associated with this collection is 1997.050.
Arrangement
Minute books are arranged in chronological order by company.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Three brothers, John, Michael J. and Thomas Tracy, organized the Tracy Towing Line in 1917. John Tracy was also an organizer of the Maritime Association of the Port of New York. The Tracy family included sisters Catherine and Helen, who also sat on the board of the various companies the family created for their tugboat and towing business. The company was located at 1 Broadway in New York City with additional offices in Brooklyn.
Ledgers (account books); Tugboats.; Minutes (administrative records); Minute books.; Tugboats |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Tracy Towing Line, Inc., 1917-1983
  - Volume 1, 1917-1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Volume 2, Mar 1, 1948-Sep 25, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Volume 3, Dec 31, 1951-May 23, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Volume 4, Feb 18, 1961-Nov 15, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Volume 5, Mar 1, 1966-Jun 9, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Volume 6, Jul 16, 1971-Apr 4, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Volume 7, May 16, 1973-May 16, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Volume 8, Aut 1, 1979-Nov 8, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- M&J Tracy Towing, Inc., 1917-1983
  - Volume 1, Oct 17, 1917-Dec 29, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Volume 2, Mar 1, 1950-Dec 3, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Volume 3, Dec 12, 1952-Oct 26, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Volume 4, Dec 21, 1956-Aug 24, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Volume 5, Sep 10, 1964-Aug 30, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Volume 6, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Volume 7, Jul 16, 1971-May 16, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Volume 8, Aut 29, 1973-Nov 9, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Volume 9, Jan 25, 1978-Nov 18, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Volume 10, Feb 24, 1983-Nov 8, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Keystone Towing Lines, Inc., 1942-1987
  - Volume 1, Dec 10, 1942-Mar 1, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Volume 2, Mar 1, 1951-Aug 1, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Volume 3, Mar 1, 1966-Mar 1, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Volume 4, May 16, 1973-Aug 1, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Volume 5, Dec 5, 1979-Nov 8, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- St. George Towing Line, Inc., 1947-1983
  - Volume 1, Dec 22, 1947-Mar 18, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Volume 2, Mar 3, 1960-Dec 15, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Volume 3, Mar 21, 1972-Nov 8, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Tracy Towing Corporation, 1952-1987
  - Volume 1, Feb 11, 1952-May 6, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Volume 2, Apr 28, 1958-Aug 30, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Volume 3, Nov 8, 1968-May 16, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Volume 4, Dec 6, 1973-Nov 8, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- W.J.T. Towing Line, Inc., 1940 - 1983
  - Volume 1, Oct 22, 1940-Oct 20, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Volume 2, Mar 1, 1951-Jan 5, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Volume 3, Mar 1, 1966-Dec 5, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Volume 4, Feb 6, 1980-Nov 8, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)